#### Contact

d.laurens@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/laurens-de-lamarche (LinkedIn) www.laurensdelamarche.be (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

Leadership
Behavior-Driven Development (BDD)
Automated Software Testing

## Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual) French (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual) Dutch (Native or Bilingual)

### **Publications**

A practical introduction to DDD and ODD coming from standard Rails

Master Thesis: Feasibility and Usability of a Generic Gamification Framework in Digital Books

# Laurens De la Marche

Staff Software Engineer at Abbove

Ghent, Flemish Region, Belgium

# Summary

I am passionate about entrepreneurship, technology, engineering and science.

I have solid programming knowledge and experience accompanied by a strong engineering background (Master of Science in Computer Science Engineering at the University of Ghent). I enjoy learning, solving technical problems and building great products.

In my spare time I try to keep myself up to date on recent advancements. I read a lot and spend a lot of time on personal projects experimenting with a wide variety of technology.

More details can be found on www.laurensdelamarche.be

# Experience

Abbove (PaxFamilia)
1 year 4 months

Staff Software Engineer (Tech lead) March 2023 - Present (1 year)

- Brussels, Brussels Region, Belgium
- Aligning high level objectives with concrete requirements through guidelines

- Responsible for technical decisions of the application team

- Setting long term goals and making sure we tackle them step by step with each step providing value
- Providing leadership bandwidth and ideas to adjacent teams (product, design, infrastructure)
- Finetuning processes and culture to accommodate the team and objectives
- Tackling hard high value issues or other development bandwidth when needed
- Clearing the way for other members of the team
- Levelling up the codebase, processes and the team

Senior Software Engineer

November 2022 - February 2023 (4 months)

Blueshift BVBA

Director and cofounder

September 2016 - Present (7 years 6 months)

Blueshift is a company that sells various consumer products online through online marketplaces. Most of these products are designed by us and improve on existing solutions. We mainly sell in the USA.

Isabel Group

Full-stack Software Engineer

December 2019 - November 2022 (3 years)

Brussels, Brussels Region, Belgium

Working on multiple software projects at Isabel Group. Mainly using Ruby, Rails, React, Docker and Openshift.

The role required putting on many different hats: development, infrastructure, processes and product. My main focus was writing code and providing bandwidth for technical and process decisions as a senior software engineer.

Vlaams Instituut voor Archivering (VIAA) Full-stack Ruby on Rails developer August 2018 - February 2020 (1 year 7 months) Gent Area, Belgium

Working as a full-stack developer on five core applications:

- one shared backend component handling data flow (Ruby)
- two customer facing applications (one B2B and one B2C) (Rails/Blacklight/ JS/Solr)
- API for internal use (LDAP/Rails API/REST/Swagger)
- one admin frontend (Rails/React)

I helped in defining the technical and business requirements. I developed numerous features both in legacy code and new projects. I helped in deploying the applications on the new Kubernetes cluster in Docker containers (Openshift/Docker/Gitlab CI).

I worked 4/5 under a freelance contract that started as a 1 month contract and got extended in scope and duration multiple times.

Brainshift BVBA

Director and cofounder October 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 3 months)

Gent Area, Belgium

Brainshift was founded to solve problems using computer vision through machine learning. We developed a prototype of a product that would classify images on small IoT devices. I was responsible for a lot of the technical work. The project did not take off commercially because of other commitments and priorities.

We are still doing consulting and open for new projects in machine learning and computer vision.

Hardware used: Raspberry Pi, Movidius, GPU

Software used: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Docker

Algorithms used: Deep neural networks (Inception, ResNet)

SYNTRA Vlaanderen / ToThePoint
Full-stack Ruby on Rails developer / Solution Architect
March 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 5 months)

Freelancer contract to work on Coosy. Coosy is a webapplication used by SYNTRA Vlaanderen. It receives data from different SYNTRA centers and makes it accessible to SYNTRA Vlaanderen employees. Administration related to SYNTRA Vlaanderen objectives is hence facilitated.

My responsibility was to fix bugs and develop new features of stories handed over by our functional analyst based on the business requirements of SYNTRA Vlaanderen.

denkGroot B.V.

Full-stack Ruby on Rails developer October 2014 - February 2015 (5 months)

Remote

I was brought as a Ruby on Rails development freelancer on the Buurtlink.nl project, a webapplication with close to a million users.

My responsibilities included the development of new deployable features in SCRUM codesprints and management of the current code in between the sprints.

Development was full-stack, every developer on the team had the sole and total responsibility over a set of the features. Those features were designed, estimated, validated and tested by the buurtlink organisation and by denkGroot. Hence teamwork and self-reliance was required.

#### Divavenue

Summer Internship: Full Stack Developer July 2013 - September 2013 (3 months)

Implementation of a web application/platform starting from requirements specified by the founders.

Mainly managing every technological aspect of the start-up:

-high-level: planning the project, prioritising tasks, financial estimates, structuring, communication with all stakeholders and potential customers.

-mid-level: choosing external services (API's) and deployment/hosting solution, devising the datamodel, decoupling in several modules, creation of different environments (eg: development/production), continuous integration/agile development.

-low-level: constructing the database, test-driven-development of the functionality of the platform, coding the first version of the design.

Being in a small team, actively participated in commercial, creative and strategic aspects of the business.

Experience acquired mainly in Ruby on Rails, Test Driven Development, Soap/XML, Rspec, HTML/CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, external cloud-based services, external API's etc...

Ministry of Foreign Affairs Assistant of PR and Communications September 2009 - September 2009 (1 month)

- -Surveillance of international news feed.
- -Processing of international news articles.

# Education

### Universiteit Gent

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science Engineering (main subject: ICT), Computer Science Engineering (main subject: ICT) · (2009 - 2014)

Coursera Online Education (2012 - 2012)

Lycée privé Sainte Geneviève, Versailles PCSI, PCSI · (2008 - 2009)